The W.A. Whitten Collection, 1962-1991 LCP2009/004
Liberian Collections
- Artifacts, Willie and Lucille Whitten collected these artifacts during their visits to Liberia in the 1960s and 1970s. They are currently housed at the Mathers Museum of World Cultures at Indiana University. In the finding aid, these items are arranged alphabetically by subject, with subcategories
  - Figurines and Carvings
    - Wood Bust Carvings
      - Moslem male with cap (medium)
      - Moslem male without cap (medium)
      - Young female facing left
      - Young female facing right
      - Young female with braided hair
      - Young female with braided hair-high forehead
      - Young female with long braids
      - Young female with plain hair
      - Young female with side view
      - Young mother and child
    - Wood Hand-God Figures
      - Female Figure
      - Yoruba Ibeji Twin Figure
  - Household Furniture and Utensils
    - Broom
    - Carrying Net
    - Chief's Chair
    - Clay Water Pot (large)
    - Clay Water Pot (small)
    - Condiment Basket – Jar type
    - Fish/Carrying Basket
    - Large Wood Spoon
    - Rice Mortar
    - Scoop
    - Spice/Nuts Mortar
    - Stools With Four Legs
      - Large Wood Stool
      - Medium Wood Stool
      - Medium Wood Stool
      - Small Wood Stool
  - Leisure Items
    - Games
      - Decorative Game Board
      - Plain Game Board (with Bean Tokens)
      - Society Game Board
    - Musical Instruments
      - Belly Harp
      - Drums
        - Medium Drum
        - Small Drum
        - Small Talking Drum
      - Iron Bells
        - Large iron Bell With Wood Stick & Metal Ring
        - Medium Iron Bell With Wood Stick & Metal Ring
        - Small Iron Bell With Wood Stick & Metal Ring
    - Marimba With Two Mallets
    - Sasa Gourd Rattler
  - Textiles
    - Boutique-Type Cloth
      - Blue Cloth #1
      - Blue Cloth #2
      - Blue Cloth #3
    - Chief's Robes
      - Robe & Cap from Local Weaved Cloth (black, blue, beige & white)
      - Robe & Cap Commercially made Cloth (bright black, white & blue)
      - Robe Probably Made from Local Weaved Cloth (beige)
    - Female Dress (blue)
    - Local Made Country Cloth Rolls
      - Dark Color
      - Light Color
    - Male Shirt (blue & white)
    - Raffia Bag (red & beige)
    - Weaving Loom Parts
      - Shuttle (oval)
      - Shuttle (rectangle)
      - Thread Filter
  - Tools
    - Smithing
      - Loma Blacksmith Bellows Pair from Vezela Town
      - Bellows
      - Bellows
    - Upland Rice Farming Tools
      - Axe
      - Machete (Cutlass)
      - Regular Hoe
      - Scratching Hoe for Rice Planting
    - Weapons
      - Knife with Brass Blade and Bone Handle (copy)
      - Sword with Sheath (copy)